Hi, and I think we should say "goodbye"
哈囉 不過我想我們應該說再見了，
because the filming is over.
畢竟影片都結束了
Why?
為什麼？
We've just talked to our father.
我們剛剛和我們的父親談過。
He doesn't want to participate in this film anymore.
他不想再參與這部影片。
It was fine with him as long as he could tell you
他會很配合--如果你讓完全
exactly what to do and what to show.
他掌控拍什麼 說什麼等等一切。
He wanted to glorify himself in front of the camera
他想要在鏡頭前榮耀他自己，
but the truth is we quarrel all the time
但事實是我們永遠都在吵架
and we can hardly make ends meet.
而且這爭吵似乎不會停止。
So, what are you going to do with
那，你眼睛的檢驗
the medical examination of your eyes?
該怎麼辦呢？
I have no idea.
我也不知道。
I would have to tell him that you want
我會告訴他，
to help me with it.
你想要幫我去做這件事。
And, you'll tell him that.
而你會負責告訴他。
Out of reach
（有摸不到邊 之意）
I'm with Karolina now.
我現在Karolina一起，
We've been watching some photos on the computer.
我們最近常在電腦上研究這些照片。
And?
所以？
Something's wrong with my eyes.
我的眼睛好像出了問題
When I sit in front of the computer,
每當我坐在電腦前面時，
I get a terrible headache.
我就頭痛欲裂
And?
所以？
Karolina smsed Kuba yesterday
Karolina 昨天傳簡訊給 Kuba
and asked him if he could help us
問他能不能幫我們
with arranging the medical examination of my eyes
安排一些眼睛的檢驗等等。
And?
所以呢？
And, he agreed but it has to be our decision.
他同意了，但是這必須你也要同意。
But why are you arranging things behind my back?
但你為什麼瞞著我做這些安排？
Karolina wrote to him, not me.
是Karolin寫信給他，不是我！
You are really messing up things.
你真的很會搞砸事情
What do you mean?
你是什麼意思？
O.K. He can help you with the medical examination,
可-以-阿- 他可以幫你安排眼睛檢驗，
but I don't want to have anything to do with him.
但我不想跟他扯其他上任何關係
I don't want to do anything against you.
但我不想做違抗你的事情
That's why I'm asking you.
這就是為什麼我會問你。
Karolina wrote to him and he agreed to help,
Karolina傳簡訊給他而且他同意幫忙，
but I want to have your permission first.
但我想要先有你的許可阿
O.K. So, go and do it, but I don't want to see him anymore.
可-----以, 去做吧，但我不想要再看到他了
There will be no more filming!
我不要再被拍了
So, you've decided to come here with your sister, right?
所以...你和你姊妹一起來這邊是嘛？
Yes. 是的
You're 16. Why did't you come with your parents?
你才 16 歲。為什麼沒和你的父母來?
Hold this book, all right?
拿著這本書好嗎
Now, look at it and tell me what you can see.
現在，看著它，告訴我你能看到什麼？
There are smaller signs here
這裡有些小標誌，
and bigger signs over there.
還有一些大的在旁邊
I can only see a different colour here.
我只能看到這邊有一塊不同的顏色
All right.
好吧。
I'm showing you my hand now.
現在我給你看我的手。
How many fingers can you see?
你能看到多少根手指？
I don't know.
我不知道。
And now? Can you see my hand?
現在呢？你能看到我的手嗎？
I can see it now.
我現在可以看到它。
Can you count my fingers?
你能數我的手指嗎？
How many fingers can you see with your left eye?
你用你的左眼能看到多少根手指？
I can't tell.
我看不出來
And now? Can you see anything?
而現在呢？你看到什麼？
No.
我看不到。
Usually, it's possible for an eye to recover provided
通常呢，眼睛是有機會恢復的，
the problem is taken care of by the parents
但需要父母非常細心的照顧
because you are still a child, aren't you?
因為你仍是個孩子，不是嗎？
The problem, however, was ignored.
然而，這問題卻被忽略了
The eye wasn't attended to with sufficient care.
這一隻眼睛沒有被好好的照顧
and now it doesn't function at all.
而現在它已經不具備該有的功能了
You're now 16 and for the last 16 years
你現在 16 歲，過去 16 年來
your eyesight has been deteriorating.
你的視力一直在惡化。
This means that it won't be possible for you to see
這意味著你另一隻眼睛很可能
with your left eye at all.
也會逐漸失去功能
Stop crying.
別哭了。
I have no plans for the future.
我對未來有沒有計劃。
Life is life.
生活就是生活。
You're in a shitty situation because you're only 16.
你面臨一個滿慘的局面，因為你才 16 歲。
I am sure I'll leave home sooner than you.
我相信我比你更早就會離開家。
Do you want to bet?
你想要打賭嗎？
Sure. A hundred zloty.
當然。一百個茲羅提。
There was one card. Actually, it was not a card
本來有一張卡片，其實不是一張卡，
but a big cup made of cardstock
是用一堆卡紙做的杯子
that we prepared for the Father's Day.
是我們為了父親節準備的。
We gave it to him with a note
我們在卡片上寫上
"for the best father in the world".
"給全世界最好的爸爸"
It was the only thing that
這是我們唯一一次真的
we really wanted to prepare for him.
很想為他做的
And, we did it out of our own will.
而且，我們那樣做是出於我們自己的意願。
That's your handwriting:
這就是你的字：
"Dad, on this joyous day I wish you good health,
爸爸，在這歡樂的一天我祝你身體健康，
best of luck and may God bless you.
祝福你好運，並願上帝保佑你。
I want you to be happy for the next thousand years
要再幸福一千年，
and I hope you'll spend this time with Mum".
我希望你會和媽媽一起度過這時光。
Sentence on behalf of the Republic of Poland
代表波蘭共和國反對
against Bożena Siankowska.
Bożena Siankowska 的句子。
And, we've got the reference number.
還有，我們找到社會號碼了。
Another reference number.
另一組社會號碼。
This is what we're looking for.
這是我們要找的。
So, we need to borrow it from Dad.
所以，我們需要向爸爸借這個。
It's enough if we copy it.
影印就好了啦
We can find her ID number at the Citizens Advice Bureau
我們可以在公民諮詢局找到她的 ID 號碼，
or take it from Grandma.
或從奶奶那邊找。
Why would they give us our mother's ID number
公民諮詢局為什麼會願意給
at the Citizens Advice Bureau?
我們她的ID號碼？
We'll just tell them
我們就告訴他們
that we're looking for our mother.
我們正在找我們的母親。
Come in.
請進。
Good morning.
早安。
We've got little information about our mother because
我們只有一點點我們的母親的資訊，
Klaudia was 2.5 and I was 3.5 years old when she left us
因為她是在 Klaudia 兩歲半，我3歲半的時候離開我們的。
and we still don't know where she is.
而我們仍然不知道她在哪裡。
Klaudia met our cousins who said she'd been put to jail.
Klaudia 遇見過一個親戚說 她去坐牢了。
We don't know if she's in Poland or abroad.
我們不知道她是否還在波蘭或在國外。
We also heard gossips that she'd been deported to Poland
我們還聽到謠言說，她曾被驅逐出波蘭，
and was in prison somewhere here.
而且曾經在這裡的某個監獄。
We have no access to any documents.
我們找不到任何相關文件。
Does she use your father's surname or her maiden name?
她不會用你父親的姓或她的娘家的姓嗎？
No idea. After the wedding, she used our father's name.
我們不知道。婚後她用了我們父親的名字。
Actually, they didn't divorce.
實際上，他們沒有正式離婚。
It was "annulment of marriage".
他們 ' 宣佈婚姻無效 '。
She could have used her maiden name.
所以她可以用她的娘家姓。
We don't know that.
我們不知道。
She was pursued by police
她在法院還在審理離婚案的時候
when the divorce case was still in court.
就被警察追補到案去了。
She didn't come to court
她沒有出席
for the marriage annulment verdict.
席法院的婚姻終止判決
We just want to know if she's alive,
我們只是想知道是否她還活著，
what's going on with her and where she is
她怎麼樣了 還有她在哪裡
According to the penal code, as the injured party
根據刑法，作為受害方，
you have access to the court files.
你有機會獲得法院的文件。
I suggest you should go to court
我建議你應該
and browse through the files
去法院查查看文件
to find all the possible information about your mother.
去找關於你母親的所有可能資訊。
This may help you get in touch with her.
這可能有助於你和她取得聯繫。
Welcome to our sanctuary.
歡迎來到我們的聖所。
Our alcohol den.
我們充滿酒精的巢穴。
So, we've arrived at the place where we drink,
所以，我們現在在我們喝酒的地方，
have parties…
開趴的地方......
Where it smells.
有臭味的地方
Where we sleep, play cards, play chess…
我們在這邊睡覺，打牌、 下棋......
This is not me.
這不是我。
This is you.
這是你。
This is not me.
這不是我。
This is you.
這是你。
Klaudia，I remember having
我記得Klaudia以前有一套
a completely different outfit at that time.
很美很美的衣服
It was so pretty.
太漂亮了
Oh, yes. A real beauty. Wait a second!
哦，對。超美的。等一下 ！
Give me some of them.
給我一些。
You're going through them so slowly.
你是看的好慢唷
We don't have many memories of our Mum.
我們對媽媽其實沒有太多回憶，
I don't remember what she actually looked like.
我甚至不記得她長什麼樣
There was only one time when she came to visit us.
只有一次在她有來看我們，
There are only three photos here.
在這裡只有三張照片。
She showed up once to give us the bicycles
她那次給出現是為了給我們自行車，
and she was wearing this white dress.
而且她穿著這件白色的洋裝。
Yes, a "superman costume".
沒錯，是超人裝。
It was a white, semi-transparent cloth and she had long blond hair.
它是一塊白色的半透明布，而且她有著長長的金髮。
She was wearing sunglasses to hide her black eyes.
她戴著太陽鏡以隱藏她烏青的雙眼。
Do you remember this gold bracelet she was wearing?
你還記得她帶著這個金手鐲嗎？
Yes, rings and earrings.
對，還有戒指和耳環。
Then, it turned out that she robbed a jeweller.
然後，原來她搶了一個珠寶商。
If I was to see Bożena again, I would…
如果我能再見到我媽 Bożena ...
She would tell you the same thing:
她會說同樣的話：
"Sweetie, I had no choice".
親愛的，我別無選擇。
I would kick her ass.
我會踢她的屁股。
I wouldn't listen to her chattering.
我不會聽她的嘮叨。
I would pay her back for all the 16 years
我會把她這十六年來
when she wasn’t here on Mother's Day…
母親節的缺席一次奉還給她
Nobody would be able to calm me down.
而且沒人能讓我平靜下來。
Maybe violence is not the best way out,
暴力也許不是最好的出路，
but kicking her ass would make me feel better.
但踢她一腳會讓我感覺好很多。
It'd be a miracle if I didn't kill her.
如果我沒有殺她，就是個奇蹟了。
Good morning.
早安
Good morning. Come in, please.
早安。請進。
Forty one.
四十一個。
Thirty four. Forty one. Here?
三十四個、四十一個。在這裡嗎？
Aha.
啊哈。
Good morning. Can we come in?
早安，您好。我們可以進來嗎?
Come in, please.
請進來。
The father doesn't know where his wife is
那個爸爸不知道該去哪裡找他的妻子，
although he tried to find her.
即使他嚐試著找她。
Her friends refused to inform him where she is.
她的朋友們拒絕告訴他她在哪裡。
The father stopped drinking two years ago.
父親兩年前戒了酒。
He is a member of Alcoholics Anonymous.
他是匿名戒酒會的成員。
He believes other members of the AA group support him.
他認為戒酒會的其他成員也支持他。
The father seems to care for his daughters.
Bożena Siankowska has been deprived of her parental rights.
Bożena Siankowska 因此被剝奪了她為母的權利。
She isn't interested in her daughters
她不是她的女兒們有興趣，
and doesn't contact them.
不會與他們取得聯繫。
How come her ID number is not in the files?
她的身份證號碼怎麼會沒有在檔案裡呢？
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
You can change your place of residence,
你可以改變你的住處，
but not your ID number!
但你不能動身分證號碼阿！
Whose fault is it then?
那這是誰的錯呢？
It's the court's fault.
這是法院的錯。
They should have the basic data.
他們應該要有這些基本資料阿。
You always want to have everything right away.
你總是想要立刻擁有一切。
Good morning. This is Bożena speaking.
早安，這是 Bożena 的答錄機。（主角的媽媽）
Please leave the message.
請留言。
Hi, Mum. We're having a walk with Tola now.
嗨，媽，我們現在正在與Tola 散步。
We need to talk about our trip.
我們需要談一談我們的旅行。
So, call me or I'll call you later. Bye.
所以，打給我或等一下我打給你，掰啦。
We've been in touch with her for only two weeks
從我們聯絡到她到現在也才兩週，
now and she wants to meet us now?
她現在就想見我們嗎？
I don't even know this woman and
我甚至不認識這個女人，
I'm supposed to visit her abroad?
我難道應該出國就為了看她？
It's more difficult for you because
這對你來說是比較困難，
you don't even remember her.
因為你甚至不記得她。
She hasn't given us enough time
她還沒有給我們足夠的時間來接受
to accept the fact that she's with us again.
[她又出現在我們的生活裡了] 這件事情
She wants to buy us one-way tickets.
她想要給我們買單程的票。
We can come only if we have return tickets.
我們可以過來只要我們有回程票。
If we have return tickets
如果我們有返程機票
and more time to think it over.
和更多的時間想一想。
Not just two weeks.
不是像這樣只有兩週。
So, she called you first or what?
所以是...你先打給她的嗎？
I called her first because
我先打給她的，
I stole her phone number from Grandma's mobile.
因為我從奶奶的電話裡偷了她的電話號碼。
And, what did you tell her?
然後你對她說了什麼呢？
At first it was the answering machine.
最初它是答錄機。
Then, I gave Tola her phone number.
然後，我給托拉了她的電話號碼。
Tola SMSed her and Bożena called her back.
Tola 傳簡訊給她然後她打電話回來
After they talked, Tola was crying.
電話接通以後Tola就開始哭了
I was furious because Bożena didn't call me at all.
我氣炸了 因為 Bożena 完全沒有打給我
I texted her to tell her how bad I felt
我傳簡訊告訴她
about it and she called me back immediately.
我有多難過然後她馬上打回來給我了
And?
然後呢？
She started crying and giving excuses
她開始哭然後開始為
for what she did in the past.
她過去做的找藉口
She's abandoned you and now
她拋棄了你，
she suddenly wants you to visit her?
然後現在她希望你去看她？
She last saw you when you were 3 and now you're 18.
她上次見到你時你是 3歲，現在你18 歲了。
Maybe she'll contact you again when you turn 30?
也許她下次聯絡你要等你三十歲？
Aren't you afraid that after you meet her,
你不怕你見到她後，
she'll disappear from your life again?
她又會從你的生活再次消失嗎?
Aren't you going to suffer even more?
這樣你不會更難過嗎？
I know it's risky.
我知道這樣風險很高
She's been in touch with everyone else but you.
她幾乎和所有人都聯絡了，除了你。
She could have talked to you just for a second
她大可跟你說說話，
to see what you're like.
猜猜你的樣子也可以阿。
She's forgotten about you
她完全忘了你然後
and now you want to hit the fucking road?
你現在要為了她去看她？
Just to see Paris?
只為了去看巴黎嗎？
To see what she's like?
去看她長什麼樣子嗎？
I don't know if I should go or not…
我不知道我該不該去......
Don't you worry about anything.
你不用擔心，現在你是跟你爸在一起，
Now you're with Dad. I'll help if I can.
而我能幫的上的我也會幫
I'll send you money from time to time.
我不時會寄錢給你。如果你想，
If you want, you can come here in five or six months.
你可以五或六個月後再過來。
Karolina will come first
Karolina 會先來，
and see what it's like here. Hello?
然後看看這裡怎麼樣。喂？
I'm here.
我在聽
She can stay with me because I live alone.
她可以跟我住，因為我一個人住
I've got a job.
我有在工作。
I haven't told this to Karolina, but I think
我還沒把這件事情告訴 Karolina
she's going through a hard time now.
但我想這對她會有點難熬
I think she has my character.
我認為她有我的性格。
You're absolutely right.
你完全正確。
That's my impression of her.
這是我對她的印象。
I've tried to learn from my own mistakes
我試著從我自己的錯誤中學習，
and I want her to do the same.
而且我想讓她也這樣做。
I don't want you girls to make similar mistakes
我不希望你們犯下
like me and your father.
我跟你爸犯過的錯誤。
I'd like you to settle down,
我希望你能定下來，
but Karolina seems to be very much like me.
但 Karolina 似乎很像我
That's why I'd like her to come here.
這也是為什麼我希望她能過來，
Maybe I could help by telling her about
我就能告訴她
the mistakes I've made.
我之前犯下的錯。
We haven't seen each other for such a long time.
我們已經好久沒有見面了。
Right.
對...
We have a chance to change things for better.
我們有機會讓一切變得更好，
And then, we'll see…
然後我們再看怎樣....
How will we recognize each other at the airport?
我們怎麼在機場認出彼此呢？
I'm 160 cm tall and I'm a blonde.
我身高 160 公分，金髮。
I'm slim and I weigh 48 kg.
我算苗條，體重 48 公斤。
What a starveling!
你是餓死鬼阿！
What?
什麼？
So, you're quite thin. Thinner that me.
所以，你很薄，比我更薄。
And, how much do you weigh?
那你有多重？
52 kg
52 公斤。
Almost my weight. How about your hair?
跟我差不多，那你的頭髮呢？
Is it long?
是長髮嗎？
Shoulder length.
在肩膀那邊
I have longer hair.
我的頭髮更長一點
Last time I saw you, you also had long hair.
上次我看到你的時候你也是長髮的。
Who is it?
那是誰？
What?
什麼？
Who is it?
那是誰？
It's a friend of mine. He drove me home.
是我朋友，他載我回家。
I've told him my children are coming over.
我告訴他我的小孩要過來了。
He'd like to say "hello" to you,
他想說 HELLO
but you don't speak French or English.
但你們不說法語也不說英語
Wait a second. I'll give him the phone
等一下，我把電話給他這樣
so you can tell him "hello".
你可以跟他說嗨
Hello.
你好。
Fuck off.
去死吧你！
It's my first flight. This is my reservation.
這是我第一次坐飛機，這是我的電子機票
Where shall I go?
我該往哪裡去呢?
Where are you flying?
你往哪裡飛?
To Paris.
到巴黎。
It's not possible to say what you're going to feel
到底你會怎麼想，她會怎麼想，
and what she's going to feel.
好像都難以預料
I'm going to tell her to keep her hands away from me.
我會告訴她不要用她的手碰我!
I wonder what she looks like.
好想知道她長什麼樣子
How did she describe herself?
她是怎麼形容自己的？
Blond hair, 160 cm tall.
金髮，身高 160 公分。
Just like me.
就像我。
She described herself very precisely.
她很精確地描述自己的長相。
I need to go. Take care.
我要走了。保重，
Say "hello" to Kasia and her son.
幫我和 Kasia 還有她兒子說哈囉，
We'll SMS each other.
我再傳簡訊給你。
Goodbye my love.
再見，我的愛。
I wonder what she looks like
我在想不知道她到底長什麼樣子，
and how they will get on with each other.
然後不知道她們相處的會怎麼樣。
Karolina will need at least three days
Karolina 至少會需要三天來告訴
to tell me everything about it.
我在那邊發生的事情。
What Bożena looks like,
Bożena 長什麼樣子、
what they did, where they went.
他們都做些什麼、他們都去了哪
I take care of Philip for 5 to 6 hours every day.
我每天照顧Philip 5 到 6 個小時。
Witek comes to collect him after work
Witek 下班後來接
and then takes him to Kasia.
他到Kasia那邊.
Would you like to have your own child in the future?
你在未來會想要有自己的孩子嗎？
In the future, yes. And, more than one.
在未來會的，而且會多於一個。
She hasn't seen me for several years
她已經有七年沒有看到我了，
and now the boss won't let her pick me up.
現在她老闆居然不讓她來接我。
She could have taken a short break
她其實可以跟老闆請個幾
to collect me from the airport. Pity.
小時的假來幫我接機阿，太可惜了。
We're going to the centre of Paris now.
我們現在要去巴黎的中心，
I hope we'll see each other tonight or tomorrow.
希望我們明天會見到彼此。
She told me she didn't work on Sundays,
她跟我說她星期天不用上班的，
but then she said she did…
但現在她又說她要上班...
It's a crazy place. Millions of people, pubs,
這地方好瘋狂。數以百萬計的人、 酒吧、
residences, monuments. Fuck!
住宅、 紀念碑。幹 ！
It's really incredible.
這真是不可思議。
Tola is going to regret she hasn't come here.
Tola 一定會很後悔她沒有到這裡來。
It's better for me and Karolina to go separately.
我跟Karolina分開過來真的比較好，
Karolina has her own questions to ask and I have my own.
Karolina有自己想問的問題而我也有我的。
Bożena will have more time to talk to us
如果我們分開過來，
if we come separately.
Bożena 會有更多時間跟我們分別說話
If we attacked her with too many questions together,
如果我們同時用一堆問題攻擊她，
she'd feel overwhelmed.
她會無法承受的。
It could be too much of a shock for her.
可能會把她嚇死吧。
So, Karolina will talk to her first
所以呢，Karolina會先去跟她談話，
and then I'll go and ask her my questions.
然後之後再換我去問我的問題，
I think everything should be fine.
我想這樣就沒問題了。
Hello.
你好。
Hi Mum.
嗨，媽。
Hi Karolinka.
嗨，Karolinka。
I was calling you yesterday.
我昨天打電話給你。
You didn't answer.
你沒有接。
I left my mobile at work.
我把手機放在公司了
Have you read my message?
你看到我的簡訊了嗎？
I haven't checked the messages.
我還沒看
They brought my phone in the morning.
他們今天早上才幫我把手機帶來。
I'm going to take a bath now
我現在去洗個澡，
and we'll meet later on.
等等我們來見面。
Listen, I've got something to do now.
嘿聽著，我現在有點忙，
Let's meet at 5 o'clock by the Eiffel Tower.
我們五點在艾菲爾鐵塔碰面吧！
O.K.
沒問題。
Fine. My heart's beating so hard. What?
很好。 我心跳超快的。什麼？
So, 5 o'clock by the Eiffel Tower.
所以，五點在艾菲爾鐵塔？
Right.
對
How do you like it here?
你喜歡這裡嗎？
It's nice. A totally different world.
很棒阿，是一個完全不同的世界
It seems nice to tourists, but it's different
對觀光客來說很棒，
for people who work here.
但是對在這裡工作的人來說卻完全不同。
I guess so.
我猜也是
I can see that she misses us and really cares.
我感覺的到她很想念而且很在乎我們，
She's interested in how we live.
她想知道我們過的如何。
It looks good. Maybe not everything is perfect,
感覺還不錯。也許不會每件事情都超完美，
but it's a good start.
但這是一個好的開始。
It's difficult to meet somebody who
要去見一個多年前拋棄
abandoned you many years ago.
你的人真的是滿困難的。
You hate this person,
你恨這個人，
but you're also somehow attracted to her.
但你也不知為何被她吸引。
You just feel it's the right moment to meet up,
你只是覺得它是一個適合見面的時機，
but it's very difficult emotionally.
但是感情上還是滿難的。
My hands are trembling. I feel like fainting.
我的手一直發抖。我覺得好像快昏倒了，
Thousands of thoughts are racing through my head.
千萬個思緒在我腦海裡狂奔。
I can control myself now but when we meet
我現在可以控制自己，
I won't be able to utter a word.
但當我們見面時我無法說出一個字。
I'll just stand still and stare at her.
我只會站在那邊然後盯著她。
Sorry, I need a drink.
不好意思，我需要喝一杯。
Right next to the entrance. Can you hear me?
在入口的右邊，你聽的到嘛？
The entrance to where?
入口在哪裡？
There's a white kiosk here.
這裡有白色的展示牌。
On your way from… What?
從你的方向......什麼？
By the stairs?
在樓梯旁邊嗎？
Fuck, I don't see any stairs here.
幹！我沒看到這裡有任何樓梯。
You don't?
你沒看到？
I don't. Wait.
我沒有。等一下。
There's a sign over there. Jesus… What?
這裡有一個標誌。耶穌......什麼？
Are you by the Eiffel Tower now?
你現在是在艾菲爾鐵塔旁邊嗎？
Yes. Let's meet right in the middle
對，我們在鐵塔正
beneath the Eiffel Tower, O.K.?
下方集合這樣好不好？
O.K. How are you dressed?
沒問題。你穿什麼呢？
Dark brown trousers and a red-brown-white top
深棕色長褲和紅色棕色白色上衣。
I'm glad I've recorded this video-letter for her.
我很高興我錄了這個影片當信先給她。
She'll have an opportunity to see me.
她就會有機會看看我的樣子。
She'll meet Karolina, but she'll also see me.
她會見到Karolina，但也會先用影像見到我。
I wonder what her reaction will be
當她看到我在螢幕上的時候
when she sees me on tape.
會是什麼反應呢？
Good morning. This is Bożena.
早安，這是 Bożena的手機。
Please, leave your message.
請留下您的訊息。
I've always wanted to have a mother.
我一直想要有一位母親。
I haven't had my mother for so many years
因為你的遠離，我有那麼多年都沒有母親。
because you've been away. I hope it'll change now.
我希望這一切現在將會改變。
I don't want you to show up for 5 minutes
我不想要你出現五分鐘，
and then disappear for another 14 years.
然後又消失個14年。
I want you to stay with me for good.
我希望你永遠留在我身邊。
Many people have told me that I look just like you.
很多人告訴我，我們長得一模一樣。
The same height, same hair, same eyes.
相同的高度，同樣的頭髮，一樣的眼睛。
We'll see if it's true.
到時候我們就知道了。